<Document>
  # Novakin

  <Box Orientation="Horizontal" HorizontalAlignment="Center" VerticalAlignment="Center">
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobNovakin" Caption="Novakin" Scale="3.5"/>
  </Box>

  Novakin are sapient humanoid forms composed of a single superheated gas. Each Novakin is made from oxygen, nitrogen, nitrous oxide, ammonia, carbon dioxide, or water vapor. They do not breathe, eat, drink, or possess conventional blood.

  ## Anatomy

  A Novakin has only two organs: a Nexus that maintains consciousness and a Core that circulates and stabilizes its gaseous form. Loss of either is fatal.

  ## Temperature

  Their normal operating temperature is [bold]373.15 K (100 C)[/bold]. Pressure-protected outerwear contains their heat and maintains this temperature. Without it, a Novakin cools rapidly, suffers Cold damage, and releases the lost heat into the surrounding atmosphere.

  Novakin resist Heat damage while below [bold]700 K[/bold], but take Heat damage if their core temperature exceeds that limit. They resist 60 percent of Radiation damage; their other damage tolerances are otherwise unchanged.

  ## Vision

  Novakin have powerful night vision but are unusually sensitive to flashes and bright light.

  ## Gas Reserve

  Your structural gas reserve leaks fastest while full and pressurized, then more slowly as pressure falls. Below a critical reserve, or while you are medically critical, its containment becomes unstable and leakage accelerates sharply. Your selected gas escapes into the surrounding atmosphere; pressure-protected outerwear reduces that leakage. Heat regulation declines gently while reserve is healthy, then collapses rapidly at critical reserve. A fully depleted reserve is eventually fatal.

  Wearing both a pressure-protected suit and helmet contains the Novakin's emitted light, leaving them dark until the seal is broken.

  Matching-gas inhalers restore reserve. They can only replenish a Novakin with the same gas selected during character creation, and can be refilled from a pure native gas tank or canister.
</Document>
